Guide to the Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Papers TAM.118
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: EGF's "Second Life", 1937-1952; 59566
  - Subseries D: CPUSA Activities, 59593
    - Personal account/date book, backdated 1925-27 Reel 8, 1948-1957; 59598 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc Reel 8, 1949; 59597 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Statement opposing confirmation of Tom Clark as Associate Justice Reel 8, 1949; 59596 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Outline for autobiography Reel 8, 1940-1949; 59595 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Statement by EGF against Supreme Court appointment Reel 8, 1949; 59594 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Subseries D-1: Election Campaigns on the Party Ticket, 59584
    - Election campaign, EGF for Representative-at Large Reel 8, 1942; 59592 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - EGF for Congress, clippings, invitation Reel 8, 1942; 59591 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook material--Bronx campaign Reel 8, 1954; 59590 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Publicity campaign for City Council Reel 8, 1957; 59589 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Speeces, campaign for City Council Reel 9, 1957; 59588 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Clippings used in campaign for City Council Reel 9, 1957; 59587 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills Reel 9, 1942; 59586 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Radio script--women in the elections, press release and pamphlet Reel 9, 1942-1944; 59585 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D-2: Trips to France, 59567
    - EGF's notes while attending International des Femmes in Frances, Nov-Jan Reel 9, 1945; 59583 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Souvenirs from France Reel 9, 1945; 59582 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Congres International des Femmes, Paris, scrapbook material, 11/26/45 Reel 9, 1945; 59581 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Notes from International Women's Conference, Paris Reel 9, 1945; 59580 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - International Women's Conference, December 1945 Reel 9, 59579 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - DW clippings on trips to France Reel 9, 1945, 1949; 59578 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Souvenirs from trips to England, mostly CP, pamphlets and publications Reel 9, 1945-1950; 59577 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Clippings from newspapers mentioning Flynn's visit Reel 9, 1949; 59576 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - International Congress of Women Reel 9, 1945; 59575 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Souvenirs from trip to France, 1949 Reel 9, 59574 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Women's Conference, France Reel 9, 1945; 59573 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Report on the problems & status of women in England, France Reel 10, 1945; 59572 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Souvenir of Women's Conference, Paris. Report on the participation of women in the struggle against Fascism Reel 10, 1945; 59571 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Draft of speech to French Communists Reel 10, 1945; 59570 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Documents adopted by the 3d session of the Councl, Women's International Democratic Federation Reel 10, 1951; 59569 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Lists of EGF articles, women in Paris and other subjects Reel 10, 1945-1950; 59568 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Series VI: Smith Act Defense, 1951-1955; 59487
  Trial documents, clippings, broadsides, fundraising and publicity materials, and other papers from the Smith Act Defense organizations started by Flynn and taken over by her sister Kathy while Elizabeth was in prison.
  - Smith Act--comments on arrests Reel 10, 1948-1949; 59565 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Financial Report at Communist Committee to Defend the 12 Reel 10, 1949; 59564 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Notes of Garden speech, 9/19/50 Reel 10, 59563 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - MS--Political Significance of Defense Work. Memo to all Districts from Defense Committee. Fall 1950 Reel 10, 59562 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Short bio of Euge Dennis, Chairman CPUSA Reel 10, 1904-1961; 59561 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - EGF speech at 1950 convention of CPUSA Reel 10, 59560 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - MS on CP early history, mostly 1920's Reel 10, [1950], undated; 59559 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook--publicity, birthday cards Reel 10, 1950-1951; 59558 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Scrapbook materials, publicity Reel 10, 1951; 59557 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Personal correspondence, birthday greetings from W.Z. Foster Reel 10, 1951; 59556 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Scrapbook materials Reel 10, 1950-1951; 59555 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - From folder marked "CP Hist" Reel 10, 1940-1959; 59554 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Smith Act--correspondence, Jacques Duclos Reel 10, 1952; 59553 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Daily Worker Reel 10, 1947-1952; 59552 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - CP History--"Some Remarks on Role of the Review Commission" Reel 10, undated; 59551 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Scrapbook materials Reel 10, 1952; 59550 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Clippings on EGF 30 day detention Reel 10, 1952; 59549 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Collected material on play "I Was a Spy for the FBI" Reel 10, 1953; 59548 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Scrapbook material I Reel 10, 1954; 59547 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbook material II Reel 10, 1954; 59546 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Loose scrapbook materials Reel 10, 1954; 59545 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Clipping on Flynn, Morning Freiheit (Yiddish) Reel 10, 1955; 59544 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Scrapbook, 1955 Reel 11, 59543 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Mother's Day Tribute, messages and speeches, text for dramatic reading Reel 11, 1956; 59542 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Pamphlets on women, mother's day, women in CPUSA Reel 11, 1950-1969; 59541 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Wm Z Foster, CP policy during trials Reel 11, 1952; 59540 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Clippings used as evidence in Smith Act trial Reel 11, 1937-1943; 59539 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - EGF in her own defense--speaking itineraries Reel 11, 1946-1950; 59538 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters, notes expressing sympathy over Smith Act activities Reel 11, 1952-1954; 59537 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Smith Act--Summary of defense proposal. Changeover after Duclos evidence. Reel 11, 1952; 59536 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Musmanno, Dolsen, Mazzinni Pittsburgh Sedition Case 1951-53 Reel 11, 1951-1953; 59535 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers, first trial Reel 11, 1951-1952; 59534 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to the defense Reel 11, 1952-1957; 59533 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to arrests Reel 11, 1951; 59532 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to bail issues Reel 11, 1951; 59531 (Box 5, Folder 8, 9)
  - Articles--McCarran/Smith Act violations Reel 11, 1951; 59530 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Smith Act trial Reel 11, 1951; 59529 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Amnesty for Smith Act violators Reel 11, 1949-1954; 59528 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Smith Act trial, clippings Reel 12, 1952; 59527 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to second trial Reel 12, 1952; 59526 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Smith Act trial, clippings Reel 12, 1952; 59525 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Smith Act trial, clippings Reel 12, 1953; 59524 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to second trial Reel 13, 1952; 59523 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to second trial Reel 13, 1952-1954; 59522 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Newspapers relating to appeals Reel 13, 1954; 59521 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Trial transcripts, summation of EGF. 1/6/53 Reel 13, 1953; 59520 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Smith Act trial reports #1-#26. April 1952 - Jan 1953 Reel 13, 1952-1953; 59519 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Published material, two pamphlets Reel 13, 1939, 1959; 59518 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Matuson Case Reel 13, 1955; 59517 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - James Dolsen, Congo. Philadelphia Tribune Reel 13, 1960; 59516 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Assorted articles--McCarran Act, "Worker" closing, Gates departure Reel 13, 1951-1962; 59515 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - EGF's work file of clippings and pamphlets on Smith Act Reel 14, 1951-1957; 59514 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Deputy Marshall McLaughlin, Smith Act, Clipping from Colliers Reel 14, 1953; 59513 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Smith Act clippings, used as evidence Reel 14, 1937-1943; 59512 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Smith Act trial document affirming District Court verdict Reel 14, 1954; 59511 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Notes for speech on Smith Act Reel 14, 1952; 59510 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Smith Act--notes on defense, some transcripts, Flynn trial sentencing Reel 14, 1952; 59509 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Smith Act--notes on Flynn trial Reel 14, 1952; 59508 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Smith Act--notes on CP history, trial Reel 14, 1952; 59507 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Affidavit of EGF re John Lautner Reel 14, 1952; 59506 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Draft of speech for trial, 4/24/52, marked history of CPU Reel 14, 1952; 59505 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - notes used in Smith Act trial Reel 14, 1950-1959; 59504 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Defense committee, financial transfers, April Reel 14, 1950; 59503 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Smith Act trial charges Reel 14, 1948-1954; 59502 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - U.S. v Flynn--Briefs, appeals, motions Reel 14, 1954; 59501 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Brief of witnesses Reel 14, 1951; 59500 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Letters, telegrams Reel 14, 1951-1952; 59499 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Press release, defense committee publications Reel 15, 1952; 59498 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Exhibit list Reel 15, 1952; 59497 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Subject index of Government proof Reel 15, 1952; 59496 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Proceedings in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit Reel 15, 1953-1954; 59495 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - U.S. v Flynn et al. Transcript Analysis, parts I and II Reel 15, 1952; 59494 (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
  - Smith Act indictment in Ohio Reel 15, 1954; 59493 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Benjamin J. Davis, parole application Reel 16, 1953; 59492 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Commonwealth of Australia v Australian Communist Party Reel 16, 1950; 59491 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Smith Act, various documents Reel 16, 1954; 59490 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Flynn's writings on sedition trial Reel 16, 1949; 59489 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Sedition trial--Dolsen, Mazzini, Musmanno Reel 16, 1950-1953; 59488 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series VII: The Alderson Years, 1955-1957; 59470
  All of the correspondence, notes, prison documents and publications used by EGF for her book The Alderson Story. Preserved here are letters to Clarens France, Murial Symington and Kathy Flynn, the three officially approved correspondents permitted EGF while serving her prison term. Scrapbook material from the publication of the book and its public reception are included.
  - Letters to Alderson from Kathy Reel 16, 1955; 59486 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Kathy's notes on Alderson prison I Reel 16, 1955; 59485 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Kathy's notes on Alderson visits II Reel 16, 1955-1956; 59484 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Draft poem, "What Do I Miss" Reel 16, 1955; 59483 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Alderson prison papers--letters, notes, clippings Reel 16, 1955-1961; 59482 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, personal release from prison Reel 16, 1957; 59481 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Alderson to A. K. Flynn, Jan 1955-May 1957 Reel 16, 1955-1957; 59480 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Alderson to Muriel J. Symington, Jan 1955-May 1957 Reel 17, 1955-1957; 59479 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Alderson to Dr. Clemens, France, Aug 1955-May 1957 Reel 17, 1955-1957; 59478 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Alderson Manuscript, I & II Reel 17, 1963; 59477 (Box 7, Folder 10, 11)
  - Alderson Manuscript, III, Alderson Eagle Reel 17, 1956-1957; 59476 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Alderson Story, galleys, master set of revisions, pp 1-223 Reel 17, 1963; 59475 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Alderson Story, galleys II, marked set Reel 18, 1963; 59474 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Letters and drawing commemorating publication of The Alderson Story, I & II Reel 18, 1963; 59473 (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - Scrapbook, The Alderson Story--book reviews, announcements, etc Reel 18, 1963-1964; 59472 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Book reviews and correspondence, I Speak My Reel 18, 1956-1958; 59471 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Series VIII: Final Years, 1957-1964; 59389
  Scrapbook materials, pamphlets and documents from Flynn's activities upon her release from prison to her death in 1964. Documents and publication and clippings from the McCarran case, trips to Russia, itineraries, speeches, clippings, and correspondence both personal and pertaining to Flynn's position as Chair of the Communist Party after the death of Eugene Dennis in January 1961. The four subseries are: A. Research on Women; B. Passport Case; C. Scrapbooks, Autobiographical materials, correspondence; D. Baxandall Materials.
  - Subseries A, Research on Women, 59459
    - International Women's Day Reel 18, 1960; 59469 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - File on Women, Internation Women, Clippings, Notes Reel 18, 1959; 59468 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - DW, Clippings on Soviet Women Reel 18, 1960; 59467 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Letters Reel 18, 1960-1969; 59466 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - On Women's Rights Reel 18, undated, [1950-1959]; 59465 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Greeting cards to EGF, Int'l Women's Day Reel 18, 1960; 59464 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Section from Reel 18, 1960; 59463 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - US Dept of Labor, Women's Bureau publications, pamphlets Reel 18, 1960-1969; 59462 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Women in labor unions, pamphlets, publications Reel 18, [1960-1969]; 59461 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - EGF from folder marked CP Hist Reel 18, 1959-1964; 59460 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Subseries B: Passport Case, 59443
    - Passport Case, Newspaper clippings Reel 19, 1962-1963; 59458 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Passport Case, U.S. Gov't documents Reel 19, 1959-1963; 59457 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Passport Case, correspondence Reel 19, 1962-1963; 59456 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Material for "Roadblock" article, McCarran Act Reel 19, 1963; 59455 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Draft, "Roadblocks to Defeating the McCarran Act" Reel 19, 1960-1969; 59454 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Passport case, brief for appellants, EGF and Herbert Aptheker Reel 19, 1963; 59453 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlet, "The McCarran Act, Fact and Fancy," by EGF, other pamphlets, notes Reel 19, 1950-1960; 59452 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Political Affairs articles, EGF Reel 20, 1960-1964; 59451 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - EGF work copies, McCarran Act, reference notes, ILD materials Reel 20, 1920-1939; 59450 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Passport case, Emergency Civil Liberties Committee Reel 20, 1963; 59449 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Passport case, EGF Mss. Reel 20, 1962-1963; 59448 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Full page story from NY Times, 10/26/63, fight against McCarthy Reel 20, 1963; 59447 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - EGF work copies, pamphlets, papers on McCarran & Smith Reel 20, undated; 59446 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - McCarran Act material, EGF work copies, "Dare We Be Free" by H. Aptheker, and "Why You Need to Know about the McCarran Act" Reel 20, 1961; 59445 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Communism, the Courts, and the Constitution, by Guttmann & Ziegler--reference EGF, work copies on McCarran Act Reel 20, 1964; 59444 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Subseries C: Scrapbooks, Correspondence, Autobiographical, 59394
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 21, 1957; 59442 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 21, 1958; 59441 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Autobiographical writings Reel 21, [1958]; 59440 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Autobiographical clippings, notes, EGF Reel 21, 1916-1963; 59439 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Gear the Party to Mass Work, CP report, by Wm Albertson, notes by EGF Reel 21, 1959; 59438 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Greeting cards and invitations Reel 21, 1950-1969; 59437 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Schedule of courses, the Faculty of Social Sciences (EGF instructor of several) Reel 21, 1959; 59436 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Speaking engagements, with misc. correspondence & clippings Reel 21, 1959; 59435 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Obituaries, John Haynes Holmes and Louis F. McCabe Reel 21, 1960-1969; 59434 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 21, 1959; 59433 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 21, 1960-1961; 59432 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - EGF papers referring to Joe Hill Reel 21, 1960; 59431 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Autobiographical chronology, date log Reel 21, [1961]; 59430 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Later autobiographical writing & notes Reel 21, 1950-1969; 59429 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Autobiographical notes Reel 21, [1961]; 59428 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Origins of CP, outline Reel 21, [1960-1969]; 59427 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - EGF scrapbook Reel 21, 1960-1961; 59426 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Current Biography, vol 22, nr 9, features bio of EGF Reel 21, 1961; 59425 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 22, 1960-1962; 59424 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 22, 1962-1963; 59423 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 22, 1962-1963; 59422 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 22, 1963; 59421 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Pocket calendar Reel 22, 1962; 59420 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Letter to Soviet comrades, 45th anniversary of October Revolution (draft?) Reel 22, 1962; 59419 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Autobiographical Ms. Reel 22, 1963-1964; 59418 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, EGF & Richard Criley, Chicago Committee to Defend the Reel 22, 1962; 59417 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence with Al Richmond Reel 22, 1963-1964; 59416 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Joe Hill songbook, Russian/English Reel 22, 1963; 59415 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Manuscript (partial), 22nd Congress, CPUSA Reel 22, 1963; 59414 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Letters to the Editors of Pravda, on its 50th Anniversary Reel 22, [1960-1969]; 59413 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Textile Labor, issues on Patterson and Lawrence Reel 22, 1962-1963; 59412 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Engagement calendar/diary Reel 22, 1963; 59411 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Autobiographical outline, "My Second Life" Reel 22, [1963]; 59410 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence re Sean O'Casey's letters Reel 22, 1964; 59409 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Letters to Roberta Bobbo & companion while travelling in USSR, returned to EGF Reel 22, 1964; 59408 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Datebook Reel 22, 1964; 59407 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Library of Congress collection list, catalogue of documents Reel 22, undated; 59406 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Copies of clippings from Dartmouth College Library, used by R. Baxandall Reel 22, 1970-1979; 59405 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence re EGF papers, from Wayne State Archives and U of Michigan. Reel 22, 1964; 59404 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Notes for lecture on turbulent 20's and the the IWW by EGF, various Reel 22, 1964; 59403 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Ms on Democratic rights (draft for speech) Reel 22, 1964; 59402 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Ms, draft, "The State of the Whole People" Reel 22, 1964; 59401 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Draft for speech, "History of CPUSA, 1919-64" Reel 22, 59400 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Autobiographical outline and notes Reel 22, 1964; 59399 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Bio as of 1964 Reel 22, 59398 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Last published piece by EGF, September Reel 22, 1964; 59397 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Letter from H. Aptheker and newspaper clippings on EGF's death, press releases by CPUSA, September Reel 22, 1964; 59396 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Flynn bibliography materials Reel 22, undated; 59395 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Subseries D: Baxandall Materials, 59390
    - Draft of biography Reel 22, undated; 59393 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence referring to Baxandall's publication Reel 22, 1970-1979; 59392 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Materials (xerox) used in Baxandall's publication Reel 22, undated; 59391 (Box 8, Folder 61)
- Series IX (Addendum): Files Obtained by Rosalyn Baxandall and Helen Camp under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 59256
  This series consists primarily of photocopied material from the files of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), Central Intelligence Agency, U.S. Department of Justice, U. S. Bureau of Prisons and other government agencies. The copies were provided to Rosalyn F. Baxandall and Helen C. Camp as a result of separate requests under the Freedom of Information Act in the mid-1980s. Because there was considerable duplication of material between the Baxandall and Camp files, duplicate files have been eliminated and the files have been arranged in one series, beginning with FBI files arranged by file number and concluding with files arranged by agency of origin.
  Individual files may contain a wide variety of documents, including intercepted correspondence of Flynn and her associates, correspondence between government officials and agents, clippings, leaflets and other radical political materials, reports or summaries of reports by agents and informants, and summarizes the contents of the Daily Worker and other publications. There may be considerable duplication of content between files, as government agencies and branches regularly transmitted material from their files to each other.
  The series begins with a folder of Baxandall requests and related correspondence; these letters were found without accompanying documents. Where request letters were found in the collection with accompanying documents, they have been filed along with those documents. The series ends with a bound volume of material secured by Baxandall through a legal proceeding (Baxandall vs. FBI, DOJ, CIA [CA - 82 - 8736]). NOTE: boxes 1-4 have been processed and microfilmed; boxes 5-6 are unprocessed and not microfilmed.
  - Flynn: Baxandall FOIA Requests; Related Correspondence Reel 23, 1985-1986; 59388 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 1 - 53 Reel 23, 59387 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 54 - 84 Reel 23, 59386 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 85 - 135 Reel 23, 59385 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 136 - 186 Reel 23, 59384 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 187 - 230 Reel 24, 59383 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 231 Reel 24, 59382 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 232 - 281 Reel 24, 59381 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 282 - 302 Reel 24, 59380 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 303 - 350 Reel 24, 59379 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 351 - 415 Reel 25, 59378 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 416 - 516 Reel 25, 59377 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 517 - 586 Reel 25, 59376 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 587 - 681 Reel 25, 59375 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 682 - 714 Reel 25, 59374 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 715 - 770 Reel 26, 59373 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 771 - 850 Reel 26, 59372 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 851 - 929 Reel 26, 59371 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 930 - 1004 Reel 26, 59370 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 1005 - 1080 Reel 27, 59369 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 1081 - 1160 Reel 27, 59368 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: 1161 Reel 27, 59367 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: Communist Party Briefs Reel 27, 59366 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1287: Referral Responses Reel 27, 59365 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1696: 1 -150 Reel 27, 59364 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1696: 151 - 330 Reel 27, 59363 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Flynn: FOIA File No. 100 - 1696: 331 - 553 Reel 27, 59362 (Box 10, Folder 9)